this code looks a little bit different
than what we saw in the previous
problems
our call to integer times is the last
evaluated line in our method once again
but this time within the block path to
times
we have an if statement
you can see that without this if
statement
if we commented it out we'll see the
same behavior that we saw earlier
when we invoke the count sheet method we
will output
0 through 4 from within the method
the method will return the integer 5 and
will output the return value of the
method
so now let's think about how this if
statement changes the behavior of our
method
on line four the conditional we provide
is
if sheep is greater than or equal to two
as we iterate through this block we'll
be counting from zero
to one to two so on our third iteration
this condition will be true sheep will
be equal to two
because of that ruby will execute line
five
on line five we have a return
remember that return will immediately
exit from the method
so before we think about the return
value of our method
let's just run our code and see this
behavior
we expect to output 0 1
2 and then exit the method so we won't
count all the way up to 4 this time
and that's what we see
when shape is equal to 2 we immediately
return from the method
so in a case like this we need to think
about what the return value of the
method will be
this time the return value of our method
won't be
5 because when we use return
to explicitly return from a method
we return the value provided to that
keyword return
in this case there wasn't any value
provided
so we can expect that the return value
of the method will be nil
and we print this using p on line 10 so
that we can see that nil
so if we don't provide a value to return
the return value
will be nil let's provide a
string to return and see how that
changes the output
running our code again you can see that
our method now returns the string we
provided return
you